Alex Windett

FRONT END DEVELOPER & UX PRODUCT DESIGNER

MOBILE: 07875 488 415

EMAIL: windettalex@gmail.com

LINKDIN: uk.linedin.com/in/alexwindett

GITHUB: alex-windett

WEBSITE: www.windett.co.uk

PROFILE

As a motivated and reliable web developer working at a software engineering and digital product design company I am currently working on the design and build of a competitor to AWS as a cloud containerisation service. This job has not only given me the opportunity to develop isomorphic JavaScript – React / Redux and Express - applications, I have also been able to give a different perspective in solving problems when it comes to user experience. I have experience of managing my clients, liaising with external developers and participating in group meetings. I have enjoyed utilising my communication skills and developing and maintaining successful working relationships with both internal and external colleagues.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

UX PRODUCT DESIGNER AND FRONT END DEVELOPER MAKE US PROUD / YLD, LONDON, N1 6AH

September 2016 – Present

• Researching, wireframing and developing SaaS applications.

- Working with both Front End and Back End
 JavaScript developers to create clean and
 maintainable applications, incorporating Ava unit
 testing and deployments with Circle CI.
- Working on small feature spikes to find the most effective library for the desired outcome.
- Conducting user research alongside stakeholder interviews through to iterating on designs by incorporating feedback from user testing.
- Acting as the intermediary between the design process and the front end visual build, ensuring consistency between the two.

FRONT END DEVELOPER BIG FISH DESIGN LTD, LONDON SW10 0QJ

November 2014 – September 2016

- Developing and deploying mobile first responsive websites from Creative Suite design files using build systems.
- Maintenance of existing sites through with Git.
- Producing designs for client approval.
- Assisting and advising account managers and designers with feasible strategies and options.
- Meeting with clients to discuss the initial brief and future proposals.
- Working closely with other developers within the company and externally.
- Learning new skills when needed and sharing knowledge with other team members, Currently driving the progression using React.js in upcoming projects.

EDUCATION

GENERAL ASSEMBLY, LONDON, E1 5JL WEB DEVELOPMENT IMMERSIVE COURSE

June – September 2014

UNIVERSITY OF NEWCASTLE-UPON-TYNE 2010 - 2013 2:1 Degree BA Geography

THE HARRODIAN SCHOOL, LONDON SW13 9QN 2002 – 2010 3 A Levels, 1 AS Level 10 GSCEs

INTERESTS

I am always interested in developing my skills further, and use my knowledge as a Front End Developer to try and improve the UX process.

Outside of work I try and fit attending meetups and conferences around a semi-hectic cycling schedule - competing in road races, a few track events and the odd end of season triathlon to name a few.